Guide to the New-York Historical Society Audiovisual Media Record Group 1974-2002 NYHS-RG 28
New-York Historical Society
New-York Historical Society audiovisual media records
1974-2002
New-York Historical Society
NYHS-RG 28
12.13 Linear feet in nine record cartons and eight document boxes.
The New-York Historical Society audiovisual media records primarily include videocassettes and audiocassettes from the late 1980s to early 1990s. N-YHS's lectures, panel discussions and concerts organized around the "Why History?" theme (1990-92) and programs connected to the bicentennial of the U.S. Constitution (1987) are especially well-documented, though many other presentations in video or audio format are also included. Audiotapes include training for docents and N-YHS education staff concerning particular N-YHS exhibitions and gallery installations. The record group is currently restricted because of the lack of appropriate playback equipment and the fragility of the tapes.
Arrangement Note
The record group is organized in three series:
Series I. Moving Images
Series II. Audiotapes
Series III. Digital Media
Accruals Note
Further accruals to the record group are expected over time.
Scope and Contents Note
The record group includes audiovisual formats, primarily videocassettes and audiocassettes, that were found in the archive as standalone objects. (Audiovisual formats found in exhibition or other files remain in those files in other record groups.) These formats date principally from the late 1980s to early 1990s, though there are some into the early 2000s. The subject matter of the videotapes includes mostly public programs, especially the "Why History?" lectures and panel discussions of 1990-1992. Educational programs, public service announcements, exhibition openings, and some History Makers award events have videos. Audiotapes also include programs, such as "Why History?," but also have a broader range of topics, including docent and education staff training for exhibitions and gallery installations. Programs related to the exhibition Government by Choice: Inventing the U.S. Constitution and other initiatives connected to the bicentennial of the Constitution in 1987 are well-represented in the record group. The record group is currently restricted because of the lack of appropriate playback equipment and the fragility of the tapes.
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the New-York Historical Society archives. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the New-York Historical Society Archives (NYHS-RG Archives). Other record groups that are processed and available to researchers and are especially related to the New-York Historical Society audiovisual media records (NYHS-RG 28) are as follows:
Much of the record group relates to public and education programs and docent training with respect to exhibition and gallery tours. Documentation about these programs can be found in the New-York Historical Society public programs and education records (NYHS-RG 23).
This record group includes only those audiovisual and digital formats found as standalone objects when the archive was processed in 2015-16. Media found in files with other documents, such as exhibition files, were left with those records. Tapes are rare in these other files, but digital formats such as CDs and DVDs are common, especially in the New-York Historical Society Museum Department records (NYHS-RG 20).
Access Restrictions
The record group is restricted. The record group includes audiovisual formats that are either too fragile to play or do not have the necessary playback equipment available or both.
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Audiocassettes; United States Constitution Bicentennial, 1987-1991; Filmed panel discussions; Filmed lectures; Museum docents -- New York (State) -- New York.; Learned institutions and societies -- New York (State) -- New York.; New York (N.Y.) -- History -- Societies, etc.; Videocassettes; United States -- History -- Study and teaching.; New-York Historical Society. Public Programs Department; New-York Historical Society -- Archives; New-York Historical Society. Education Department
- Series I. Moving Images, 1985-2002; 8.3 Linear feet
  Arrangement Note
  The container list includes an inventory of items in sequential box order. The items appear to have been fitted into boxes in no particular order and the inventory reflects that.
  The subject descriptions and dates used in the container list were taken from the labels on the item. [Bracketed] descriptions were added by the processing archivist. The formats (e.g., VHS, Betacam) noted in the container list were determined by the archivist's observations; where the archivist was uncertain of the format, the description "format?" was used.
  Scope and Contents Note
  The series includes moving image formats, primarily videocassettes in VHS, Betacam, and U-Matic formats. The bulk of these date from the late 1980s and early 1990s and, judging only from the labels, the subject matter primarily concerns programs held at N-YHS. Most extensively documented in these tapes are the lectures, panel discussions and some concerts presented as part of the "Why History?" series that ran from 1990-92. These series linked various programs to particular themes, including "Race and Class" in 1991 and "What is American?" in 1992. Educational initiatives are also documented here, including high school student mock Constitutional Convention debates, the Liberty Scholars partnership with Bank Street College, and the Lab School collaboration with I.S. 44.
  The moving images also include public service announcements (PSAs), interviews, and exhibition openings. Many of these relate to N-YHS's exhibition Government by Choice: Inventing the U.S. Constitution and other tie-ins to the bicentennial of the Constitution in 1987. Tapes of special events are also included, such as some of the History Makers Award ceremonies (including the second one, in 1989, honoring Malcolm Forbes) and former President Bill Clinton's July 2001 appearance.
  - National Portrait Gallery "Faces of Colonial America" (VHS), 1988 August 8 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - WWOR-TV The Joe Franklin Show with Arthur Marks from the N-YHS (U-matic?), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Reminisce #1-6 (2 tapes) (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Morgan Stanley Dean Witter and Company. Historical Society Dub (2 tapes) (VHS), 1998 December 12 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Why History? What is American? Rhythms of New York concert program produced in conjunction with the the Ethnic Folk Arts Center (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Luman Reed Lesson 12 & 13 / I.S. 44 (VHS), 1991 April 23 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
    Mr. Edwin Scott's Class.
  - Italics: The Italian American Magazine. [TV show] Episode 38. (VHS), 1991 November (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
    Post-it on front reads Karen on WINS December 12, 1988- Home Front Dale and Wendy on WFUV FM.
  - History Makers Award Gala Time Code Window Dub (VHS), 1989 October 30 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - My Name is Malcolm Forbes and Award Ceremony (VHS), 1989 October 30 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Dr. Irma Watkins-Owens and the Workshop on African-American History for Seneca Village Project (VHS), 1992 February 28 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Third Annual Mock Constitutional Convention for High Schools (2 tapes) (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - The Joe Franklin Show with Dr. Elizabeth McCaughey. "Government by Choice" (VHS), 1987 September 30 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - "Why History? What is American?" Keynote Lecture (VHS), 1991 February 5 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Senator Domenici. Documentary on the Bicentennial of the U.S. Constitution (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - The New York Public Library (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - "The Press and The Public" Project Demo Reel (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - No label (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - I.S.44/Fordham and N-YHS Meeting (VHS), 1991 January 14 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - MCC Without Titles (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - History Makers Award Gala. Window Dub of All (VHS), 1989 October 30 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Third Annual Mock Constitutional Convention (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Bicentennial Connection Project (VHS), 1989 October 25 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Bank Street Liberty Scholar Evaluations. Second Cycle (VHS), 1991 March 16 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Bank Street Liberty Scholar Evaluations. Third Cycle (VHS), 1991 May 11 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Bank Street Liberty Scholars Exhibit Construction. Cycles Two and Three (VHS), 1991 March 9 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - 300th Anniversary of the NY Supreme Court (VHS), 1991 February 1 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Report on the N-YHS presented on Daiwa New York View (5 minute prime-time TV Show Aired Weekly in Japan) (VHS), 1992 March 8 (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - "The Shape of the World" Parts 1-6 (4 tapes) (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 1, Item -)
  - Insights. Museum Visitors Attitudes, Expectations. A Focus Group Experiment (VHS), 1991 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - Project: Mock First Congress (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - Three PSA's concerning "Government by Choice" (2 tapes) (U-matic), 1988 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - WNYS-TV Presentation of "Where the Experiment Began: NYC & the Constitution" (U-matic), undated (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - N-YHS PSA for "Francis W. Edmonds: American Master in the Dutch Tradition" (2 tapes) (U-matic), 1988 January (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - WNYW-TV: "Big Apple Minute: Constitution" (U-matic?), 1987 October 30 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - WWOR-TV: The Joe Franklin Show with Dr. McCoy [sic] (Betsy McCaughey) (U-matic?), ? September 30 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
    Outside and Inside labels read.
  - WABC-TV: New York Views with Delia Fine on the "Constitution" (U-matic?), [1987] November 14 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - WNYW-TV: McCreary Report with Ben Hooks on the "Constitution" (U-matic?), [1987] November 15 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - "My Name is Malcolm Forbes" (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - Slide Review of History Centers Forum (VHS), 1995 May 20 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - "New York, New York!" A Five Minute Visit to The World Capital of Excitement (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - WABC-TV Eyewitness News:"Paine Webber Art Gallery" (VHS), 1991 September 19 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - Arts in America with Walter Cronkite: A Video About the National Endowment for the Arts (VHS), 1992 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - Niagara Art Show at the N-YHS Dub (U-matic?), 1986 January 22 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - NBC Nightly News: "Statue of Liberty Story" by Dr. James Bell, N-YHS (U-matic?), 1986 July 3 (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - "Audubon Birthday" with Phyllis George (2 tapes) (U-matic?), 1985 May (Offsite-box 2, Item -)
  - N-YHS PSA for "Francis W. Edmonds: American Master in the Dutch Tradition" (2 open reels, tape?), 1988 January (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
  - Bill Clinton at N-YHS (VHS), 2001 July 17 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
  - Why History? "Historical Perspectives: Race and Class in New York City" Keynote Lecture by Cornel West (VHS), 1991 February 5 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
  - Primetime (VHS), 1991 June 20 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
  - Patriotism Under Fire: The Vietnam War (Show #9) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 May 6 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A101, A102, A103 and B101, B102, B103.
  - Learning History/Panel Discussion (Show #8) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 April 25 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A24, A25, A26, A27, A28, and B24, B25, B26, B27, B28, B29.
  - American History Film: The Civil Rights Movement (Show #7) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 April 22 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A21, A22, A23, and B21, B22, B23.
  - Whose History? Panel Discussion (Show # 6) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 March 29 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A17, A18, A19, and B17, B18, B19, B20.
  - Women and World War II (Show #5) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 March 25 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A13, A14, A15, A16, and B13, B14, B15.
  - New York Intellectuals and Radical Politics (Show # 4) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 March 11 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A10, A11, A12, and B10, B11, B12.
  - The American Indian and The West (Show # 3) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 February 25 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A7, A8, A9, and B7, B8, B9.
  - A House Divided: The Civil War (Show # 2) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 February 4 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A4, A5, A6, and B4, B5, B6.
  - "Why History?" Keynote Address (Show # 1) (4 VHS tapes), 1990 January 25 (Offsite-box 3, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A1, A2, A3, and B1, B2, B3.
  - Colonial Williamsburg presents "In Trust To America: A Tribute to Colin & Nancy Campbell" (VHS), 2002 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - Rufus King (VHS), undated (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - "The World of Tomorrow" Directed by Lance Bird and Tom Johnson (VHS), 1984? (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - N-YHS Awards Gala (2 VHS tapes), 1989 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - N-YHS Awards Gala (Betacam), 1989 October 30 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - N-YHS Awards Gala (U-matic), 1989 October 30 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - WNYC-TV: "Where the Experiment Began: New York City & The Constitution" (U-matic), undated (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - Central Park Exhibit (with music) (U-matic), undated (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - Clinton-Jefferson PSA's: "Government by Choice" (U-matic), 1987 September 3 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - Opening of the Jackie Robinson Exhibit at N-YHS on April 15, 1987 (U-matic?), 1987 April 15 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - Bonnie Durrance Productions. "The Jackie Robinson Story" Part II (U-matic?), 1987 March 12 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - "Iron Ponies" Toy Train Operating Society (3 tapes) (U-matic?), 1986 October 8 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - WNYE-TV: "Inventing the Constitution." Dub Master (U-matic?), undated (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - "Tiffany Artist in Glass" (U-matic), undated (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - WABC-TV: Blizzard of 1888 (U-matic?), ? January 15 (Offsite-box 4, Item -)
  - Why History? The Civil War (6 Betacam tapes), 1990 February 4 (Offsite-box 5, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A4- A6 and B4- B6.
  - Why History? (Dr. Raymond Paredes) (6 Betacam tapes), 1990 January 25 (Offsite-box 5, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A1-A3 and B1- B3.
  - "Indians" (6 Betacam tapes), 1990 February 25 (Offsite-box 5, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A7-A9 and B7-B9.
  - N-YHS Awards Gala (6 Betacam tapes), 1989 October 30 (Offsite-box 5, Item -)
    Consists of R1-R4, "Show cards with titles", and "Sign Only."
  - New York Intellectuals and Radical Politics (6 Betacam tapes), 1990 February 25 (Offsite-box 5, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A10, A11, A12 and B10, B11, B12.
  - Learning History/Panel Discussion (Show #8) (10 Betacam tapes), 1990 April 25 (Offsite-box 6, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A24-A27 and B24-B29.
  - American History Film: The Civil Rights Movement (Show #7) (6 Betacam tapes), 1990 April 25 (Offsite-box 6, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A21-A23 and B21-B23.
  - Whose History? Panel Discussion (Show # 6) (8 Betacam tapes), 1990 March 29 (Offsite-box 6, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A17-A20 and B17-B20.
  - "Rosie" Show (7 Betacam tapes), 1990 March 25 (Offsite-box 6, Item -)
    Consists of Rolls A13-A16 and B13-B15.
  - N-YHS "History Maker" Award (VHS), 2000 November 15 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
  - N-YHS "History Maker" Award Gala includes "Citizen Mike" (VHS), 1999 November 17 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Music from China. Show 91-11 (VHS), 1991 April 20 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR # 46-51.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] No House No Home. Show 91-12 (VHS), 1991 April 21 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# 52-57.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Life and Survival Parts 1 and 2. Show 91-13 (2 VHS tapes), 1991 April 24 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# 58-64.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Prejudice and The Other New Yorker. Show 91-15 (VHS), 1991 May 8 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# 69-74.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Voices to be Heard. Show 91-14 (VHS), 1991 May 5 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# 65-68.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Images of the City. Show 91-5 (VHS), 1991 March 3 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR #A18-A21.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Los Pleneros de la 21. Show 91-7 (VHS), 1991 March 23 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# 27-30.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Historical Perspectives. Show 2-91 (VHS), 1991 February 13 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# A5-A8.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Contemporary Issues. Show 91-4 (VHS), 1991 February 27 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Calabria Bella. Show 3-91 (VHS), 1991 February 23 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Bridging the Gap. Show 91-8 (VHS), 1991 March 27 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# 31-34.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] New to the City. Show 91-9 (VHS), 1991 April 7 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# 35-38.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Responsibility, Change, and Power. Show 91-10 (VHS), 1991 April 10 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# 40-45.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Opening Lecture. (8 Betacam tapes), 1991 February 5 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# A1-A4 and B1-B4.
  - "My Lai" (6 Betacam tapes), 1990 May 6 (Offsite-box 7, Item -)
    Consists of CR# A101-A103 and B101-B103.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Historical Perspectives (8 Betacam tapes), 1991 February 13 (Offsite-box 8, Item -)
    Consists of CR# A5-A8 and B5-B8.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Bridging the Gap. Show 91-8. (4 Betacam tapes), 1991 March 27 (Offsite-box 8, Item -)
    Consists of CR# A31-A34. Note: No B camera roll.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Images of the City. Show 91-5 (8 Betacam tapes), 1991 March 3
    Consists of CR# A18-A21 and B18-B 21. Event 5.
  - Why History? [Race and Class] Contemporary Issues (10 Betacam tapes), 1991 February 27 (Offsite-box 8, Item -)
    Consists of CR# A13-A17 and B13-B17. Event 4.
  - NHK-TV Japan: Advanced English Conversation with Betsy Gotbaum, 1995 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
    Includes a VHS videocassette of the Gotbaum interview that aired in Japan, and a companion booklet to the video with an English transcription under the title, "Making Historical Objects Accessible and Exciting." The booklet also includes a transcription of an interview with N-YHS Curator of Architectural Collections Mary Beth Betts on the topic of "Photographs as History."
  - Three PSA's from the N-YHS "Government By Choice" Exhibition (open reel, tape), 1987 September 3 (Offsite-box 17, Reel -)
    Includes PSAs for Program 1: George Clinton and Program 2: Thomas Jefferson.
- Series II. Audiotapes, 1974-1991; 3.46 Linear feet
  The subject descriptions and dates used in the container list were taken from the labels on the item. [Bracketed] descriptions were added by the processing archivist.
  The series includes audiocassette tapes (and a few open reels and a tape cartridge) dating primarily from the late 1980s and early 1990s. Judging only from the labels, the subject matter appears to primarily include public lectures and presentations held at N-YHS and training/background sessions, likely for docents, educators and other N-YHS staff responsible for conveying exhibition interpretative comments to the public. Many of the tapes include the lectures, panel discussions and some concerts presented as part of the "Why History?" series that ran from 1990-92. Other tapes include lectures by guest speakers and N-YHS curators that related to exhibitions, including those by N-YHS museum curator Annette Blaugrund on Paris 1889 (1989) and The Taste of Andrew Carnegie (1991), N-YHS Librarian James Mooney on Putting New York on the Map (1988), and Professor Mosette Broderick on McKim, Mead & White's New York (1991), to name just a few. Tapes related to docent training include, among many others, museum curator Ella Foshay on the Niagara (1986) and Hudson River School (1987) exhibitions, curator Tim Burgard on Thomas Cole's The Course of Empire (1989), and N-YHS educators Carole Slatkin and Jane Lattes on Audubon (1987) and firefighting (1985) exhibitions, respectively. Some tapes provide collection overviews, including an "Introduction to Department of Public Programs: Highlights for Teachers" (1986) and Ella Foshay on "Treasures of the New-York Historical Society" (1988). Many tapes related to programs connected to the bicentennial of the Constitution are found in the series, including guest curator Betsy McCaughey on the exhibition Government by Choice: Inventing the U.S. Constitution (1987) and the series of educational programs broadcast on radio.
  - Early American Leaders Training Session (Debby Longman), 1985 September 12 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Ethnic Festivals for Children, undated (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
    Cory Munson and Sarah Carnahan.
  - Ethnic Festivals for Children, undated (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
    Photographer Roberta Intrater.
  - Folk Art. Jeff Warner and Jeff Davis (2 tapes), 1989 December 9 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
    Folk songs for children.
  - Folk Art. Laverne Kelly, undated (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Folk Art. Music of the Adirondacks (2 tapes), 1989 September 19 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Folk Art. Catherine Schwoeffermann--Threaded Memories: Quilters of Upstate New York (2 tapes), 1989 November 1 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Folk Art. Karen Lux-History and Traditional Arts in Upstate New York, 1989 October 25 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Henry Graff Lecture. The Presidency, 1987 October 7 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Hail to the Chief Lecture. Robert Caro and Ted Morgan, 1986 October-November (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Holtzman Lecture. New York City Government, 1987 March 25 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - James Flexner Lecture, undated (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Firefighting Training Tour. Jane Lattes, 1985 August (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Nina Gray Lecture. Furniture, 1989 December 20 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Elizabeth Garrett Lecture. The Quest for Comfort: Daily Life in 19th Century America, 1988 April 21 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Wendell Garrett Lecture. The Ardent Spirits of Independence: Drinking Habits in a New Nation, 1988 April 7 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Constitution Training #4, undated (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Benno Schmidt Lectures. Constitution, 1987 September 30 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Betsy McCaughey. Constitution Training (2 tapes), 1987 March, July (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Sarah Conahan. Constitution Training, [1987] (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Constitution Exhibition Walk Through. Betsy McCaughey, 1987 September 14 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Lillian Schneider. Constitution Training (2 tapes), 1987 March, May (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - I.Smith Reid Lecture. Constitution and Minorities, 1987 July 22 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Constitution Training, undated (Offsite-box 9, Item -)
  - Nick Clark. Edmonds Training, undated (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Colonial New York Training, 1989 March (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
  - Bel Sonore Chamber Players, 1990 October 21 (Offsite-box 9, Cassette -)
    With Soprano Deborah Friedrich.